Think about the average person
to weigh a pound per program.
Here they are.
That's very easily.
Second time.
Are they going to be so hard? Oh
my god, I would die.
OK, it's 10.30.
So we'll get started.
Good to see everyone again.
Announcements, do you know
homework four is due on Sunday.
You can't use slip days on it.
Homework three, scores and
solutions are up.
And the grade report has been
updated.
Midterm one is on Tuesday, of
course.
And you know that we have a
practice midterm tomorrow from
2.30
to 5.30,
as is said on the court's
website.
The plan is if you come, it's in
1013 Dow, same room where the
real midterm is, right across
the hall here.
We're going to have printed out
copies of the spring 26 midterm
one.
You'll have two hours to take it
as if it's a real exam.
And then in the final hour, we
will take it up.
And that final hour will be
recorded, but it will be pretty
casual.
And then on Tuesday, the day of
the exam lecture here will just
be office hours style review,
so I'm not going to prepare
anything, come to me with your
questions,
attendance won't be required,
so you don't have to come just
for the sake of checking in, but
I'll be here and this will be my
office hours.
The plan for today is to briefly
recap the idea of linear
independence, which recall was
the main new idea on Tuesday.
And then what we're gonna do is
we're gonna introduce lots of
different words that
formalize ideas that we've
already seen so there are no
like new big ideas today rather
What we're going to do is
formally define what a subspace
is and what the dimension of a
subspace is note This is not a
new idea for two lectures Now
we've been saying things like
the span of these two vectors in
r3 is a two-dimensional subspace
of r3 But I just want to tell
you what a subspace actually is
and what the dimension of a
subspace actually is now We'll
say right off the bat is that
you know technically today's
lecture is in scope for the
midterm But the questions that
relate to today's lecture that
would appear on the midterm Will
involve things that you could
have answered before today So if
there's some like totally new
thing that you only learned
about in today's lecture But
didn't appear in the yesterday's
lab or the current homework I
wouldn't put that on the midterm
But it's something about asking
about the dimension of a
subspace like that probably will
appear and technically we only
defined subspaces and dimensions
here, but we've already used
those ideas before.
So sort of I'll make the midterm
in a way,
or I have made the midterm in a
way such that it represents what
you've spent your time thinking
about.
There's not going to be a ton of
questions about brand new stuff
that only appeared today.
One other thing I wanted to
point out is that I've been
working on a few other things
with the course website.
And one of them that I figured
out to get to work yesterday is
having questions that are
randomized in the site.
So for example, I mean, this is
a simple one that I just made as
a proof of concept,
but it tells you to type in the
dot product of these vectors.
Let's make one of these right
ones.
These are on 45 plus 16,
61.
And it tells you if they're
right or wrong, and you can
shuffle the answers, and it'll
ask you to put more in.
I mean, this is the simplest
thing I could think of, and
maybe we didn't need this one
specifically, but you can
imagine we could have one that's
like,
find the equation of the plane
spanned by these two vectors.
In the last class, it seemed
like people wanted more practice
with that, so I'll add one of
those in, and as the semester
progresses, I'll think of more
of these.
And if you think of some of
them,
let me know, I can try and embed
them in the notes.
And it's pretty cool, the
solutions update whenever we
change the randomization.
So if we shuffle,
make a new one,
the solutions are now different.
All right,
cool.
So recall last class,
the main new idea or the new
term
was that of linear independence.
So we said vectors v1,
v2,
through vd,
all of whom
have the same number of
components, let's say they all
live in Rn,
are linearly independent
if either,
well, I shouldn't say it that
way,
but there's two equivalent ways
of thinking about what it means
for these vectors to be linearly
independent.
What was the intuitive way?
The first definition we get.
None of the vectors
can be written
as linear combinations of the
others.
And just to save some space
here, I'll write this as LCs.
Okay, it's the first time using
that abbreviation here, so I
should write it out.
Linear combinations of the
others.
And what was the more formal
way? And you saw some proofs
involving this more formal way,
or something similar to that in
yesterday's lab.
Same.
Was there something,
we'll say the first one, that's
like,
you can't set the model equal to
0?
That's the second thing I'm
asking about.
Yeah, yeah.
So the second, more formal
definition
is that the only way
to make the
0 vector as a linear combination
of the vectors
is taking zero of the first
vector
plus zero of the second vector
all the way through zero
of the last vector.
Okay, so they're linearly
independent.
It's the only way they can be
combined to make the zero vector
is if you take zero of the first
plus zero of the second, and so
on.
Otherwise,
they are linearly dependent.
And what I want to emphasize is
that these are two equal or
equivalent
definitions.
And after class on Tuesday, I
remember saying this, And we
talked about, like, OK,
well, here's an example of
pretend v3 is equal to 2v1 minus
5v2.
So one of the vectors is a
linear combination of the
others.
Here is why that means you can
make the zero vector with them.
But then after class, I was
like, why don't we just draw out
an example?
And I added this to the notes.
And I think someone asked this
in office hours, which is what
made me think about this.
Where's my new Good Notes
sticker?
Oh, man, where'd it go? Anyways,
here, let me find it here.
Here.
So here are two equivalent ways
of thinking about this.
What I have for us are three
vectors on the left in which
2v1 minus 5v2 is equal to v3.
Do we agree with that?
v1 and v2 themselves aren't
drawn, but it's just a
hypothetical example.
Imagine I have some vectors
where 2v1 minus 5v2 gives you
v3.
What that means is if you take
2v1 minus 5v2 minus v3, you get
back to the 0 vector.
You get back to the origin.
What that means is if you have
some vectors in which you can
make one of them using a linear
combination of the others,
well, then that also tells you
you can make the 0 vector using
a linear combination of all of
those vectors together.
If you just reverse,
see that pink vector v3,
if you reverse its direction,
now if you add all three of
these, it's like a cycle that
gets you back to the zero
vector.
What this is saying is that
these two definitions that I
wrote,
the first one being none of the
vectors can be made as a linear
combination of the others, and
the second being the only way to
make the zero vector is by
taking zero of each one.
Those are really the same thing
because of this picture.
Okay,
so to be clear here, are the
vectors v1, v2, and v3 linearly
independent in this picture?
No, they're not, because you can
make the zero vector by taking a
non-zero linear combination.
Or because V3 is a linear
combination of V1 and V2.
Okay, so these vectors are not
linearly
independent.
And of course another term for
not linearly independent is
linearly dependent.
OK.
What questions do we have with
the definition for what it means
for vectors to be linearly
independent?
And the intuitive thinking you
should have is just these
vectors are linearly independent
if every one of them contributes
something new to their span.
Every one of them is a new
building block.
They are dependent if at least
one of them can be made using
other ones.
Sam,
you had a question?
I have a question.
Yeah.
If it was just any two of these
vectors, they would be
independent.
Yeah.
So pretend my collection of
vectors was just v1 and v2,
then yeah, they're linearly
independent.
You can't make v1 with v2 or
vice versa.
Similarly, if you had just v2
and v3,
they're also linearly
independent.
But now that you have all three
of them,
well, you can make at least one
of them with the others, so the
collection as a whole is not
independent.
And so that brings me to an
important thing I want to
clarify.
Linear independence is a
property of a collection of
vectors.
If I just write one vector,
it
may or may not be linearly
independent.
It depends on what collection
you're saying it belongs to.
OK,
other questions about the
definition of linear
independence?
Doing OK so far?
All right,
so like I said,
what I want to do is formalize
some of the ideas we've already
seen.
And so now we're looking at
ideas in chapter 4.3.
I want to start by defining the
idea of a vector space.
Now,
the idea of a vector space is,
okay, suppose we were in a more
theoretical linear algebra
class.
I mean, you probably think this
class is pretty theoretical, but
I mean from like a graduate,
like if you're taking a 400
level math department linear
algebra class.
What they would say on the first
day is that linear algebra is
about vector spaces.
And they would say, give you
this abstract definition that a
vector,
you know, I said a vector is an
ordered list of numbers.
What they would say is a vector
is an element of a vector space.
And a vector space,
all it is is a collection of
objects that support two
important properties.
We're thinking abstractly here.
A vector space is a set of
objects,
usually that set is called v,
that support two operations.
If you had to guess,
what are those two operations?
And of course, the objects are
called vectors.
What do you think the two
operations things in a vector
space satisfy?
Addition and scalar
multiplication.
Good, addition and scalar
Where did this come from? Well,
if you think back to the first
day in which I introduced what a
vector was,
I said those are the first two
operations that vectors can do.
You can add two vectors together
and we visualize that,
and you can scale a vector by
scalar.
So what does addition mean?
What does it mean for these
objects to support addition? it
means that suppose you have two
elements of the vector space.
Why don't we call them u and v?
What this tells you is that
their sum is also an element of
the vector space.
So I have this collection of
objects who,
if you add two of them, you get
another object that is in the
set.
What does scalar multiplication
mean?
Well, what that tells you is
that suppose you have one item
in the collection,
v,
and you have a scalar that isn't
necessarily in the collection,
but is just a number, like let's
say it's a real number,
that tells you that the scaled
version is also an element in a
set,
OK?
Now, if I'm thinking of these
objects, and I'm being like
intentionally abstract, because
I'm going to tell you some
examples of vector spaces that
aren't vectors in the way that
you would think of them.
If I have a collection of
objects that I can add and
scalar multiply, what is the
term that I would use for the
general operation I can do to
these elements.
If I can add them, and I can do
scalar multiplication,
what would I say that these
objects can do in general?
Jobendy? Linear combinations?
Yeah, they support linear
combinations.
So elements of a vector space
support linear combinations.
OK?
Now you may say this seems a
little redundant.
Like you've already told me that
I can add and scale or multiply
them.
It's like what is really new
about this?
The new thing, and we're not
going to spend a ton of time
talking about this, but it's
like important for you to know,
is that vector spaces don't need
to be made up of vectors in the
way that we've seen them before.
Here's a vector space that
you've probably never thought
about before.
The set of polynomials
with degree,
let's say,
equal to 3.
So again, we're not looking at
vectors the way that you've
thought about them before.
We're thinking about functions
now.
But it turns out that there are
vector spaces made up of
functions.
So is the set of polynomials
with degree equal to 3 a vector
space? What would that mean? It
would have to mean that you can
take two elements of the set.
But here, the elements are
functions,
not vectors, that I would write
as little lists.
But they'd be functions.
And it needs to be the case that
if I take any linear combination
of these functions, like
something times u of x plus
something times v of x.
Don't need to call them u and v.
I'm just using that to mimic the
notation on the last slide.
I could have called this f and
g.
It needs to be the case that if
I multiply the first function by
2 and the second function by 7
and add the results,
the new function 2u plus 7v
is also in the set.
So let's make up an example.
2x cubed minus x squared plus 7x
minus 9,
and x cubed plus 4.
These are two elements of the
set of polynomials with degree
equal to 3.
If I add them,
do I get a new polynomial with
degree 3?
Sure.
If I multiply them by scalars,
do I also have polynomials with
degree 3?
Sure.
But you should see that there's
something slightly wrong about
the definition of the vector
space I wrote on the page.
And why is that?
Got it.
What if the x had a negative 2x
cubed?
Good.
And if you added them, you would
no longer have a polynomial to
be equal to.
Exactly.
Or what if I did u of x minus 2
times v of x, which is the same
thing as what you're saying,
right?
What I just said two slides ago
was that a vector space is just
a collection of things that if
you take any linear combination
of them,
they still obey the properties
of the collection.
But here,
do you agree that if I took 1
times the first function minus 2
times the second function and
looked at what that new function
would be, it wouldn't have an x
cubed term.
That 2x cubed would subtract out
with a negative 2 times x cubed
in the second, and it wouldn't
be a polynomial of degree 3.
So as I've written it, v is not
a vector space.
But we could change it to be by
just changing this requirement
to be less than or equal to 3.
And that is a perfectly valid
vector space.
If you take two functions or two
polynomials who have a degree
less than or equal to 3
and take any linear combination
of them you want,
you're also going to get back a
new polynomial whose degree is
less than or equal to 3.
And that's what makes these
polynomials a vector space.
So this is an abstract idea.
And it's not one that we're
really going to spend that much
time on in this class.
But it comes up often enough in
machine learning that you just
need to know about it, that you
will hear about vector spaces
that are made up of things that
don't look like vectors that
you've seen.
And all that really means is
that whatever those objects are,
whether in the future they're
matrices or some other more
complicated thing,
all that means is that these
objects, you can take linear
combinations of them and they
still give you back objects in
the set.
Paul.
Are you finding why f and v have
to be less than 3
but not greater?
Well, if you add two polynomial,
If you add two parabolas, you
don't get something that's more
higher degree than a parabola.
Same kind of idea.
But if you did x squared plus
negative x squared,
it could no longer be a
parabola.
Yeah,
good.
OK,
are we convinced that this is a
vector space? It's sort of
abstract, but it's like a
collection of things that you
can take linear combinations of.
We agree?
OK.
Now, I should say the vector
spaces that we normally work
with we always work
with Rn where n depending on the
situation is replaced with a
specific number like two or
three but Rn is an example of a
vector space okay it's a
collection of vectors that can
be added in scalar and multiply,
OK?
And vectors in Rn
are sometimes called Euclidean
vectors.
Does anyone know where the word
Euclidean comes from?
Yeah, ancient Greek
mathematician invented a lot of
ideas or thought about a lot of
ideas in geometry and that sort
of corresponds to the fact that
we think of the vectors that
we've seen in our class so far
as being objects in geometry
that have a length and a
direction and we can create
other geometric structures from
them.
Okay,
my point is that vector spaces
could be made up of things that
don't have geometry like
polynomials Okay,
if you're curious you can look
into the idea of like what is
the dot product between two
polynomials?
Okay,
someone had to think about that,
right? Like what if you wanted
to come up with vectors that
didn't look like lists of
numbers and you wanted to take
the dot Product between them.
What would that be?
Turns out it involves
integrating the product of the
function Okay, and that involves
calculus now We're not going to
talk about that, but I'm just
telling you that there's a whole
other world of stuff like this
out there
So that's what a vector space
is, but that's not a term we
really used before today.
The term we used before today
was that of a subspace.
Now the picture you should have
in your mind is that
a subspace is itself a vector
space contained within
a bigger vector space.
So suppose v is a vector space.
All that means, remember, is
that v is a set of objects that
will allow you to add and scalar
multiply those objects.
And that S is a subset
of V.
You can come up with lots of
subsets that are not subspaces.
Subspace is a different word
than subset, and we'll look at
some examples that clarify this
in just a bit.
S is a subspace of
V if,
what do you think makes a subset
a subspace, if you had to guess,
based on the picture that I've
drawn?
Say V is a big collection of
objects.
Say it's a collection of
vectors,
vectors in R2 if you will.
I can make up any subset of
vectors in R2 if I want.
I could say,
think of all the vectors in R2
whose first component is 17.
That's a subset of vectors in
R2.
But it's not a subspace.
What do you think a subspace
must satisfy?
Yeah?
Do subspaces have to be proper
subsets of V?
Do they have to be all of V, or
does it have to be like? It can
be all of V.
So R2 is a subspace of itself,
for example.
Zara? Well,
every element in the subspace is
also a subset.
Every element in the subspace is
also a V.
That is true, but that's true
from the fact that I'm saying it
has to be a subset.
So a subspace is like a special
subset,
but it's special for what
reason?
You have to guess.
Here's what it is.
The main idea is that a subset
is special and called a subspace
if it is closed under addition
and scalar multiplication.
What that means is if you take
two elements in the subspace and
take any linear combination of
them,
the result is still within that
subspace.
It's still in that smaller part
of the vector space.
That is,
if you take linear combinations
of vectors that live in here,
those linear combinations all
also live in here.
They don't escape out into the
bigger vector space.
So it's like a little
neighborhood that you can't
escape.
The way that my sort of like
high school math club coach
would put this was that if you
put two elephants in a cage and
a third thing comes out, but it
has to be an elephant.
That's all I think about this.
If you put two vectors in a
subspace,
OK, that's weird.
Let's not say you put them in a
cage, but you take
a linear combination of them,
what you get back is another
thing in that subspace.
So this should already sound
familiar to things that we've
seen before.
We looked at the plane spanned
by two vectors in R3,
and we saw that any linear
combination of those vectors
that spanned the plane
also lived on the plane.
You can't escape the plane just
using linear combinations.
So this is how this is,
like, we're formalizing things
we've already seen.
So how might I write the
definition here?
Suppose u and v are in s.
What that means is their sum is
also in s.
Of course, it means it's also in
v, but I'm saying,
if you take two elements of this
little neighborhood and add
them,
the result is also in that
neighborhood.
Similarly,
if v is in S and c is a scalar,
cv is also still in S.
And then also,
the zero vector needs to be in
S.
Otherwise, scalar multiplication
wouldn't work, because then you
wouldn't be able to multiply
elements by zero,
OK? OK, so note that S itself is
its own vector space.
These two lines that these
elements support addition and
scalar multiplication tell you
that S is a vector space.
You should think of it as a
vector space within another
vector space.
That is closed.
That's the property.
Now you might say,
well,
what subset wouldn't be a
subspace?
Let's think of some examples.
And if you look at the extra
practice exercises in
yesterday's lab, there were a
few of these,
but we didn't talk about this in
lecture, so maybe this was a
little hard to think about.
Let's suppose we're thinking of
R2.
So our vector space V is R2.
And let's say S is the set of
all vectors in R2
where the x component is greater
than or equal to 0
and the y component is greater
than or equal to 0.
This is a perfectly valid subset
of vectors in R2.
So I can make up any subset I
want.
Visually, what does S here look
like?
If I had to color this in and
try and depict what this
collection of vectors looks
like, where would it live?
Do you want to see possible
vectors in the first quadrant?
Yeah, it's all of the vectors in
the top right quadrant,
OK?
So any vector whose endpoint
lives here, when I draw it from
the origin,
is in this collection.
Is this collection a subspace?
At first you might think, yeah,
sure, why not?
If I take two vectors that live
in here,
call this one v,
call this one u,
you add them up,
yeah, sure.
u plus v is going to look
something like that.
If you start with two vectors
whose components are greater
than or equal to 0,
and you add the two vectors,
the new vector's components will
also be greater than or equal to
0.
So addition is good.
And the 0 vector is also
included, because I said x and y
must be greater than or equal to
0.
But what does this not satisfy?
Hold on.
Can you multiply by negative?
Yeah, I need to be able to take
any scalar multiple of these
vectors,
and it should still be in the
collection.
But it's not.
It's escaping the cage here,
so to speak.
If I multiply u by a negative
scalar,
it escaped.
It's not in the collection.
So is this S a subspace?
No, it is not.
So hopefully this clarifies the
difference between a subset and
a subspace.
A subset is just any collection
of vectors in R2, defined by
whatever rule you want.
And usually, that rule will be
written out in set builder
notation.
A subspace is a subset that
obeys very specific properties.
OK?
So here,
S is a subset,
but not a
subspace of R2.
OK,
so I'll be clear on why this set
S is not a subspace of R2.
If you take linear combinations
of things in the set,
they aren't necessarily at least
still in the set.
OK.
So that's not a subspace of R2.
Can you tell me an example that
is a subspace of R2?
Tell me an example of a subset
of R2 that is also a subspace.
Paul? Is R2 itself a subspace?
R2 itself is a subspace of R2.
Yes,
that is true.
Because if you take any two
elements in R2,
take any linear combination of
them, it's still an R2.
Yes.
But can we think of one that
isn't all of R2?
OK,
so your answer then is, what if
we take all of this and this?
But it's possible then to take a
linear combination that looks
like here plus some amount of
here That ends up here depending
on you know, if you go like
really far there and then
something not like that It may
still escape containment
Yeah,
if you make like the first entry
and one of like the majors are
like in this like vector like a
zero, okay
Close face.
So like if the first entry
always was a zero and then the
entry was Second entry was
anything else.
So you're saying like consider
the vectors like 0 1 0 2 0 3 0 4
0 5 OK,
visually, what would that look
like?
Yeah,
if we look at all the vectors
whose first component is 0,
they all live on this line.
But then we're like, wait,
what's special about this
vertical line? It doesn't need
to be vertical.
Any line through the origin is a
subspace of R2.
And you kind of already knew
this because last class, when we
talked about the span of a
vector in R2, we'd say it was a
one-dimensional subspace of R2.
So let's take a look here.
So for example, consider a line
through 0, 0
in R2.
And let's just pretend we have
some vector that spans it,
like v.
Call this the vector 1, 2.
So the line that v spans,
which may look like this,
that is a subspace of R2.
Why?
Why is this line a subspace of
R2?
Yeah.
If you take the linear
combination of two elements of a
line,
you're taking the linear
combination of two linearly
dependent vectors to the same
line.
The reason it's a subspace is
that if you pick any two vectors
that live on the line and take
any linear combination of them
You want the result is still
gonna live on the line
Okay, let's test it out.
If you don't believe me again.
I don't think you don't believe
me, but
Let's pretend.
This is one vector that lives on
here.
Call it a half of V and let's
pretend
This is another vector that
lives on here negative 3 V
If I take a linear, if I add a
half of v and negative 3v, which
is a linear combination of
vectors that live on the line,
I just get another vector that
lives on the line.
There's no way you can escape
the line by just taking linear
combinations of things that live
on it.
Any linear combination
of vectors on the line
will also be on the line.
There's no way you can escape
this line just just by taking
vectors that live on it and
taking linear combinations of
it.
So this line is a subspace of
R2.
In fact,
any line that contains 0, 0
is a subspace of R2.
Why do we need it to contain 0,
0?
Well, there are several reasons.
But one of them is that every
subspace,
if we look at the properties of
subspaces I defined a few slides
ago,
every subspace needs to contain
the 0 vector.
So if I drew a line that didn't
go through 0, 0,
we'd be done.
We could say, I know this is not
a subspace because it doesn't
contain the 0 vector.
But usually, other things will
also be broken about a subset
that doesn't contain the 0
vector,
OK?
Could someone remind me how I
would write this line
in set builder notation? If I
say it's the span of v,
how How would I write it in set
builder notation?
We did this, a lecture or two
ago.
How would I write it in set
builder notation?
I was going to say when x equals
y, but that would just be one
line.
That line would be a subspace,
but it's not this line
specifically.
This is...
Yeah.
It would be like you have like x
of x as first component and 2x
as second component.
Sure, yeah.
And all real numbers.
Yeah, there's a few ways you
could write this.
One is to say it's the set of
all vectors of the form x 2x,
where x is a real number.
Perhaps a more common way you'll
see this being written, though
it's exactly the same, is being
the set of all scalar multiples
of the vector 1, 2,
where t is that scalar is a real
number.
t is a common choice here.
Sometimes you'll use a.
OK,
you could use x.
I mean, it doesn't matter what
placeholder you use.
Anyways, this is indeed a
subspace.
Any linear combinations of
vectors that live on here
is a subspace.
Are we convinced of that?
OK.
OK,
now why don't we consider a line
not through the
origin?
I know it's not a subspace
because it doesn't
contain the zero vector.
But there are other problems
with this line.
It's not just that it doesn't
contain the zero vector.
What else is not good about it?
Suppose what you should be
thinking of here is the
collection of all vectors whose
end points live on this line.
If this line were a subspace, it
would have to mean that I can
add or scalar multiply
any vector that lives on here,
and the result is also on here.
But what if I take this vector v
and double it or multiply it by
really anything?
Where is it going to live?
It's not going to be on this
line.
If I multiply this vector v by
2,
the result is not on the line.
And the reason for this is that
the line looks like the span of
a vector, but it's shifted to
not start at the origin.
And remember, we talked about
this last class,
or two classes ago.
This is what's called an affine
line.
Doesn't contain 0, 0.
And I'm not going to talk too
much about this right now, But
the main idea here is you can
describe this line, as we said a
few classes ago,
as being the span of some
direction vector offset by a
displacement vector or a
position vector.
So you can say that this line,
pretend this direction vector
was, I don't know,
the vector 3 comma 1.
Is this line the span of 3, 1?
No, because the span of 3, 1
would have to contain the
origin.
It would be down here.
But it's the span of 3, 1 once
you add whatever this second
vector I've drawn that goes
vertically is to every vector in
the span of 3, 1.
So you have to describe it with
an offset
plus the span of another vector
because it doesn't pass through
the origin.
But anyways, it is not a
subspace
because if you took a vector
whose endpoint lives on the line
and multiply it by any amount,
it doesn't also live on the
line.
But if the line passes through
the origin, as we saw here,
well, then you take any vector
that lives on the line and
multiply it by whatever scalar
you want,
the new vector is still going to
live on the line.
So do you see why this is a
subspace, but a line that's not
through the origin isn't?
Question, yeah.
So you said,
does living on the line mean
that one of your endpoints is on
the line?
How you should think of it is
that living on the line means if
you draw the vector from the
origin, And it's entire, like
the entire vector is on the
line.
Oh,
OK.
Can you move me?
Yes.
I was just wondering,
why is the line to the 1
a non-half-line line?
The same is also true, but if I
take this vector a half v,
and I draw it anywhere,
OK, well,
it points up and to the right.
But I could draw it up here or
down here.
It still also lives on the line.
But if I take this vector v, I
guess maybe that's another way
of thinking about it.
That should be the case that no
matter,
I guess what you're saying is,
what if I draw this vector at
half v, but draw it over here?
You could do that.
Yeah, the easiest way to think
about it is when you draw them
from the origin.
Yeah,
good question.
OK,
line through the origin,
subspace.
Line not through the origin,
not a subspace, But it's called
an affine line and a more
general term is an affine
subspace because you can imagine
this extending to higher
dimensions
Okay
Here's another thing to think
about here is a
function
In r2
Do you think it is a subspace of
r2?
OK, and it is a subset.
Like, the subset is if you
consider all vectors whose
endpoints live on this curve.
OK, you could think of this as
being like, pretend this is the
function f of x.
You could think of this as the
set of all vectors x,
f of x,
where x is a real number.
So vectors that live here would
be things
like this vector and this
vector.
These are all vectors that live
in the set.
Is this a subspace?
Again, no, it's not.
Why not?
Why did you take your head no?
You can multiply any of them by
any number.
It's not going to be in the
line.
Exactly.
If you take this vector out here
and multiply it by 1.1
or 1.0001,
it's just going to extend
slightly past the curve.
It's not going to be on the
curve anymore.
So what I'm hoping to convey
with this example
is that subspaces have this flat
nature to them, which is what
enables all scalar multiples of
things in the subspace to also
be in the subspace.
When you have this curvature,
it removes that property.
And the reason I drew this
function in particular is that
it also passes through the
origin.
So I didn't want you to over-fit
to thinking a function that
contains the origin is a
subspace.
So here the scalar multiple is
not on
the graph.
So this is not a subspace.
Subspaces are flat.
And the first time I used the
word subspace, there was another
word that started with an S that
I told you to think of a
subspace as.
I said, just think of a subspace
as being a fancy word for a
what.
Yeah?
Slice.
Yeah.
So you should think of a
one-dimensional subspace.
I haven't formally defined what
a dimension is yet,
but we're getting there.
We should think of this line as
being a one-dimensional slice of
R2.
That also passes through 0, 0.
This would be a weird-looking
slice of a cake if it had all
these curves.
A regular cut of a knife would
be straight.
So a line in R2 is a subspace.
And hopefully, it's not too
much of a stretch to tell you
that a line in R3 or R4 or R17,
those are all also subspaces as
long as those lines contain the
origin.
Do we agree?
OK.
Now, what about a plane in R3?
This is going to be not a good
drawing.
But imagine the plane
in
R3 that contains
the origin.
Do we think this is a subspace
of R3?
I'm seeing some yeses.
Why do we think that this is a
subspace of R3?
Is it because it can be
multiplied by the 0 vector as
well as any other scalar, and it
will still be in the plane?
Correct,
but to be clear,
the it you're referring to is a
vector that lives on the plane.
Yeah.
Well,
it has to support two things.
It has to support yes.
If I take any vector that lives
on the plane and multiply it by
any scalar I want, including 0,
the result is still also on the
plane.
That's true.
If you take a vector that lives
in my plane
and multiply it by whatever
number I want, it's still going
to be on the plane.
I mean, this is a small iPad
case, but you can imagine it
extends infinitely.
But it also needs to be the case
that if I take any two vectors
that live on the plane and I
take any linear combination of
them I want,
the result I get back is also on
the plane.
And why do I know that that's
the case?
Why do I know that if I took
these two vectors in red that
live on the plane,
that any linear combination, OK,
let me not use red here.
It's not.
I need to see.
Why do I know for sure that any
linear combination of these
two blue vectors also will live
on the plane?
I have a question.
If you multiply it to get big
enough when they escape the
plane, are you imagining it? The
plane extends infinitely.
Yeah, this is just a drawing of
it and that's important to
remember planes
Just like a line has no
beginning and end a plane also
has no beginning in it
Why do I know for sure that if I
took any two vectors who live on
the plane again what you should
think of that as meaning if I
draw the vector starting at the
origin, the entire vector is on
the plane.
I took any two such vectors,
like these blue ones,
and took any linear combination
of them, why do I know for sure
the result is also going to live
on the plane?
Why do I know for sure the
result is also going to live on
the plane?
Yeah?
Was there an R2?
You remember, like, escape the
R2 plane?
Well,
remember, here I'm dealing with
vectors in R3.
And this is a subtle thing.
Vectors in R3 all have three
components,
like an x amount, a y amount,
and a z amount.
Vectors in R2 all only have two
components, an x amount and a y
amount.
So a plane,
I think what you're getting at
is that it's like a flat section
of R3,
but it's still in R3.
It's like similar to R2 in that
it's like a flat plane-looking
thing.
but R2 is a universe of vectors
that only have two numbers in it
in them.
R3 is a universe of vectors that
have three vectors in them.
So it has something to do with
the fact,
it's something to do with this
plane.
Did you have an idea?
No?
Yeah?
None of these vectors can have a
component pointing out of the
plane, so no matter how you
combine them,
they can't escape it.
Exactly.
I think the idea you're getting
at is that one of the things
we've seen over the past few
lectures
is that two vectors are all you
need to span a plane in R3.
And what is the span of two
vectors?
It's the set of all of their
linear combinations.
So what this means is by
definition,
this plane is the set of
everything you can make with
these two vectors.
So can you escape the plane? No,
because the plane is defined to
be the extent of what you can
make with these two vectors.
And so while these two vectors
span this plane,
They're not the only pair of
vectors that span this plane.
So do these two.
And so do these two.
As long as they pick any two
vectors that don't point in the
same direction that live on the
plane,
their span is this entire plane.
What that means is,
here's an experiment that you
could try,
take three pairs of vectors that
live on some hypothetical plane.
For all three pairs, take the
cross product of them
and then use that to find the
equation, Ax plus By plus Cz
equals 0.
It's always going to give you
the same equation.
The cross product may be double
the length or triple the length,
but then you could just divide
by 2 or 3 and get the same
equation.
Okay?
And so,
to be clear here,
remember
any
two vectors
that aren't
scalar multiples each
other,
span of plane,
I should say in R3,
remember the span is the set
of all possible
linear combinations.
So sort of by definition,
this plane is a subspace because
it is the extent of everything
you can make using any two
vectors that live on it.
So the main idea, and this is
where I'll give you a little
break for attendance, but I want
to say this big idea before we
get into the next thing here,
you should think of spans of a
collection of vectors as always
being a subspace.
And equivalently,
any subspace you can think of is
spanned by some collection of
vectors, which you might call
building blocks.
So what I mean by the reverse
direction
is that pretend I just drew this
plane,
or I just say, OK, consider the
plane 2x plus 3y minus 7z equals
0.
I can always find some number of
vectors
whose span is that plane.
So given vectors, I can find the
plane.
Given plane, I can find vectors
that span it.
So the big idea here,
the span of a collection of
vectors is a subspace.
And every subspace
is a span,
spans our subspaces.
Okay, we're going to take a
little bit of a shorter break
just because we're a little
short on time.
It's 11.22,
we'll start at 11.25,
but let's also do attendance.
There
you go.
Okay, thank you very
much.
Would these be vectors that span
the vector space?
Yes.
Yeah, OK,
so, right.
So Josh and I are going to just
have a subset of subspace.
The problem is that Josh here
has to apply it.
And we don't have to do the
work.
So we're going to get our
packet.
And then we're going to get some
subspace.
So now we're going to have this
It's the same as the one that I
was talking about.
But you can still put in some
subspace.
So what? It does all my thought,
too.
I could have summed it up.
a lot.
Here's a half B and B-3B.
You can think of those being
different vectors.
You add them, it still just
escapes.
It's like the ship of Theseus,
where you replace every part and
you ask if it's the same.
It's kind of funny, because I
was sitting in a group chat for
a team that I'm not talking
about anymore.
Everyone checked in?
Anyone still waiting?
I think I had, like,
one group.
I understand that they still
count as new.
OK.
We've replaced every member.
All right.
So the big idea here is that the
span of a collection of vectors
is a subspace, and every
subspace can be spanned by some
vectors.
The final two words I want to
introduce before we just look at
a few examples are a basis for a
subspace.
And this will be a smaller,
the dimension of a subspace.
Now, the dimension of a subspace
is something that we have an
intuitive understanding of
already.
If we go back here,
a plane,
I've taught you to think of this
as a two-dimensional subspace of
R3.
Why? Well, it's because it kind
of looks flat.
It kind of looks like a sheet of
paper.
It kind of looks like it's just
the xy plane, but it's just in
3D.
A line through the origin, I've
taught you to think of that as a
one dimensional subspace of R2.
Or if a line is in some higher
vector space,
you'd think of it as a one
dimensional subspace of R3 or R4
or whatever.
But what is the dimension
actually? Let's take a look.
First, we need to define a
basis, because the definition
for a dimension involves a
basis.
A basis for a subspace
S is a set of
vectors
that obey two properties.
The first
is that they are linearly
independent.
The second is that they span
the whole, or maybe I'll say
entire,
subspace S.
So what you should think of is
that a basis for a subspace is
like the minimum number of
building blocks you need to
reach everything in the
subspace,
or sorry, not the minimum number
of building blocks, but it's
building blocks that you need to
make the whole subspace.
And they're minimal in that
every one of them is needed and
there's nothing useless in
there.
Like, there's no redundant
building block.
Think of a basis as an
essential, or as
a minimal set of
building blocks.
Now, we haven't even looked at
an example of finding a basis.
But based on this definition,
if I give you a subspace, how
many bases can you find for it?
And bases is plural for bases.
If I give you a subspace, how
many bases does it have?
What are we thinking here?
Yeah?
It would be infinite.
Infinite.
Why?
Let's go back to this line and
think about it from this
perspective.
All right.
So if the basis here would be 1,
2, you could also do 2, 4.
Yeah.
All a basis for this subspace,
which is this line through the
origin, would be
is a set with just one vector in
it,
whose span is this whole line.
But there's infinitely many
vectors I could say this line is
the span of.
This line is the span of 1, 2,
sure.
But it's also the span of a half
and the span of negative 3,
negative 6.
There's infinitely many vectors
that span this one line.
And any one of them forms a
basis for this subspace.
Similarly, if you go back to
this plane,
this plane, yes, it's the span
of two vectors in R3.
But which two vectors in R3 span
this plane?
There's no one answer to that.
And what I tried to depict for
you here is that there are lots
of pairs of vectors that span
this plane.
And any pair of them together is
a basis for this plane.
OK?
A subspace has infinitely
many bases.
OK.
Given that, what do you think
the dimension of a subspace is?
Yeah, exactly.
The dimension of a subspace is
just the number of vectors that
every basis for it would have.
What does that mean?
Well, let's go back to this
plane.
There are infinitely many bases
for this plane.
I've drawn three of them for you
here.
These two blue vectors span the
plane, these two black vectors
span the plane, these two purple
vectors span the plane.
But what's common amongst all
three of those bases is that I
could only write two vectors.
What would happen if I tried to
write a third?
What if I said,
okay,
why don't we toss in a third
vector in the blue collection,
and say these three vectors span
the plane?
What's wrong with that?
Or like what is problematic
about that? Emma.
The third vector would be?
It's fine.
Go for it.
The third vector would be
linearly dependent, which would
violate the definition of what a
basis is.
Exactly.
These three vectors,
do they span the plane?
Sure.
But that doesn't make them a
basis.
In order for them,
and maybe I'll leave this as an
example here.
This is not a basis,
but they span the plane.
In order for a set of vectors to
be a basis,
not only do they need to span
the subspace,
but every one of them needs to
be essential.
They need to be linearly
independent.
And those three vectors are not
linearly independent,
because I can make one of them,
any one of them, using the other
two, because they all live on
that same plane.
So that's what makes a plane
two-dimensional.
It's that every basis for the
plane would have two vectors in
it.
Okay, so now we have formal
definitions for the notion of a
basis and a dimension
and I want to look at two
examples that help crystallize
these ideas.
One is slightly more tangible,
one is slightly more abstract,
okay, and I think this will be a
good way to wrap up today's
lecture.
So why don't we start with an
example? So why don't we
consider the plane 2x,
numbers don't really matter
here,
minus 5y minus 7z
is equal to 0.
What I want you to do is find
two
possible
bases.
So that's two sets of vectors is
what I'm asking for and then
find the dimension.
Discuss with the people.
7 dot x, y, z equals 0, equals
0.
Oh, of course, we can do that.
Let me find out how we can
exploit that.
Oh, 1, 1, 2, 3,
4, 5,
6, 7,
8, 9, 10,
11,
12, 13, 14, 15,
16, 17,
18,
19,
20,
21,
22, 23, 24, 25,
26,
27,
So,
one one's on that direction,
right, and the seven's funny,
so,
like,
do the one and cross it, then
you'll get below one.
Yeah, just one.
Okay.
This needs to be equal to zero.
X, Y, Z,
P, U,
Q, X,
X.
You're putting the cross in the
direction here.
You just can't add up each
other.
The inspector can never become
the inspector.
Okay,
what are we thinking here?
Let's find two possible bases
for the plane.
What am I really asking for?
Two linearly independent lines
that are on the plane?
Two linearly independent vectors
that are on the plane,
yeah, correct.
So let's come up with one.
One pair, that is.
Yeah, go for it.
I have one.
Okay, that's fine.
111.
Yes, I made the numbers easy, so
that would work.
What's another one?
Now, why can I not put 2, 2, 2
here?
It's on the plane.
Hang on.
Because that would be linearly
dependent.
Yeah, that would be dependent
with 1, 1, 1.
And if I just look at the span
of 1, 1, 1, 2, 2, 2, it's not
the whole plane.
It's just a line that 1, 1, 1
and 2, 2, 2 both live on.
So I've got to put something
that's not a multiple of 1, 1,
1.
But other than that, I could put
whatever I want.
Yeah.
It'd be like 1, 0, 1.
But 1, 0, 1 is not on the plane.
That's the thing.
So it has to be another vector
that's not a multiple of 1, 1,
1, but is on the plane.
2, 9, 7.
Sure, how'd you cook that up?
I'll be honest, I just put in 2.
And then I thought, what's a
multiple of 7?
I said 49.
And then I'm like, what do I
need to fill in? Yeah,
so that's the kind of thing you
might do here.
Like okay, you just put
something random for the first
one that gives you four and then
you might say, okay Well that
this will give me 49 and 7 times
7 is 49.
Okay, that's perfectly fine
answer There's infinitely many
you could come up with Someone
give me a different basis and
sure you could just say take the
first one and multiply both
Vectors by something you could
do that You could also do like
the first plus the second and
the first minus the second
You could do the first plus the
second and just the second.
All of those would be fine.
What if you didn't know this
answer, though?
Think of two other vectors.
Here's the way that I would do
this.
You can just look at them two
numbers at a time.
How do I cancel out the 2 and
the 5? I could just put 5 and
negative 2, and then the third
thing could be 0.
5, negative 2, 0.
Really what I'm looking for are
vectors who are perpendicular to
2, 5, negative 7.
All right, that's the normal
vector for this plane.
So if I dot 2, 5, negative 7
with 5, negative 2, 0,
the 0 lets me ignore the
negative 7 at the end,
and the 2, 5 cancel out the 5,
negative 2.
Similarly, how do I look at just
the second two
components?
Well, I could zero out the first
one and then put a 7 and a 5,
because I already had a negative
7.
I can get there without really
needing to do much arithmetic.
Alright,
again,
there's nothing more correct
about these answers,
there are infinitely
many bases.
But all of them have the same
number of vectors in them,
and that number of vectors in
each of these bases tells you
the dimension of this plane.
And that is what?
Two.
Questions with this first
example?
The easiest way to know if that
line's on the plane,
the original plane,
any line.
Oh, this one?
Any line in general.
So why was the 1, 0, 1 not in
that plane? Because if I put a 1
here, a 0 here, and a 1 here, I
would get negative 5 on the
left, which is not equal to 0.
The vectors,
if you take this to be x, this
to be y, this to be z,
it needs to satisfy this
equation.
So one way that might help you
think about this is that this
plane is really the set of
vectors x, y, z,
where the components satisfy
this rule.
So with the strategy to approach
a problem like this, to pick a
number for one of the variables
and then solve for the others?
Totally.
Yeah, that works just fine.
And that's effectively what I
did in my two examples, where I
just made one of them zero,
which makes it easier to look
at.
Yeah.
So we knew that there is only
two independent factors here,
just because we know that this
is the equation for a plane.
Yes.
So now,
the next example I want us to
work on is one where we won't
already know the dimension.
So there's two that I'd like to
work on, one that we will
realistically get through.
Here, let's consider the
subspace
spanned
by these vectors.
1, negative 1, 0, 0,
0,
1, 1, 0,
6,
negative 6,
0,
14,
0, 0, 0, 1,
and 0,
3,
3, 7.
And I'm trying to relate this to
questions you worked on in lab
yesterday.
In lab,
I believe there was a question
that worded it exactly this way.
But what we said was,
find a linearly independent
collection of vectors whose span
is the same as the span of the
vectors we gave you.
All that really means, using the
words we know about today,
is find a basis for the span of
these vectors.
The current homework has
questions like this.
I believe yesterday's lab had
We're going to do a question
like this right now.
A question like this may be on
the exam.
This is a key idea.
Find a basis that is a linearly
independent collection of
vectors whose span is the same
as the span of all of these.
Are questions for a basis always
going to be phrased as a basis
for a span, or could a basis be
for something else?
Well,
every subspace is a span.
But I could ask, find a basis
for this.
And that would be a different
question?
Well, it's the same.
It's a similar question, but
it's worded differently in that
here,
you don't know.
I didn't give you any vectors
that are on the subspace.
You'd have to figure that out
using this equation.
Whereas in this question, I'm
saying,
here are five vectors that live
in this subspace.
Consider the span of all five of
them.
Turns out, as we're about to
see, you don't need all five of
them to span the subspace.
A minimal set of however many
vectors it ends up being is all
you need to span the subspace,
that minimal set you'd call a
basis.
So a basis is always referring
to a span or a subspace,
then?
A subspace is a span,
yes.
Thank you.
Yeah,
that's the key.
So are we clear on the question
here? I'm asking you for a basis
for this subspace.
What that means is I'm asking
you for a minimal set of vectors
that I need to make the whole
subspace.
And the technique we briefly
mentioned on the end of
Tuesday's class, but you worked
through in lab yesterday is you
look at the vectors from left to
right, and you include vectors
in your linearly independent
subset, which is the word we
used before I defined basis.
But now you know it's a basis.
You include vectors in your
basis
whenever you can't make one
vector using the other ones
you've seen.
The thing is, remember,
the basis itself, there's no
order to it.
So it doesn't matter if I read
right to left, left to right, or
if I look at the vectors in a
convenient way.
Here's what I want to illustrate
here.
So let's find a basis for S.
Let's start by looking at the
first vector.
1, negative 1, 0,
0.
If that's the first vector I've
seen,
can't make it using nothing, so
we'll include it.
So our basis now has 1, negative
1, 0, 0.
What's the next vector in the
list?
0,
1, 1, 0.
Can we make that using the
vector we've collected?
No, you cannot.
How do I know I cannot?
Well, because this vector has a
1, where the other vector we had
had a 0.
You can't multiply anything by 0
to get a 1.
So we know for sure you can
include it.
Here's where you've got to look
at the whole list to make things
simple.
If the next vector I considered
was 6, negative 6, 0, 14,
then I'd say, yeah, sure, I can
to make that using the first two
vectors I collected.
So I'd add that to my basis as
well.
And that's fine.
There exists infinitely many
bases for this subspace that
include this vector also.
But it looks a little ugly.
No offense to it.
But I chose it deliberately
because it is a linear
combination of other vectors
that are written up here.
How can I make this vector using
some of the other vectors that
are written up here?
Bella?
You can do 6 times the first one
plus 14 times the fourth one.
Yeah.
6 times 1, negative 1, 0, 0
gives you 6, negative 6, 0, 0.
And the way you get the 14 down
here is you take 14 of this
building block.
What that means is I could put
this here,
Or I could put 6, negative 6, 0,
14,
both would be fine.
What I'm trying to emphasize
here is don't blindly look left
to right because then you might
see that there's like a more
convenient vector later down the
road that makes it easy to show
the other things are linear
combinations of the convenient
ones.
So what I would do is I would
look at this and say, okay,
well,
I can include either of these in
my basis, but I'm just going to
include 0, 0, 0, 1 because it
makes the arithmetic simpler.
And the order in which these
vectors were written does not
matter.
So now pretend I've included
that.
Do I put this vector in my basis
now?
No, I don't, because if I, let's
just call these vectors v1,
v2,
v3,
v4,
and v5, I've already included
v1, v2, and v4.
But v3 is just equal to 6v1
plus 14v4.
It's a linear combination of
things I've already seen.
And a basis needs to be linearly
independent,
so I should not include it.
That's why I'm not going to
include this fellow.
What about the last vector, 0,
3, 3, 7?
Do I include that?
No.
Why?
Well, it's also a linear
combination of things I've
already collected.
It's 3 times v2,
plus 7 times v4.
So I'm also not going to include
that either.
This is just one possible
answer.
Another possible answer could
have been,
keep the first two,
and keep v3 or v5,
because if you keep, say,
v5,
you can subtract three times
this vector to give you 0,
0,
0, 7.
And then that allows you to make
the fourth component of your
vector whatever you want, which
is what this vector allowed you
here.
What I'm getting at is that
there is no one right answer.
But there are, if you're asked
to find one answer,
there are convenient ways of
going about doing that if you
look at the vectors all rather
than forcing yourself to look
from left to right.
But these are both
valid
bases for the subspace.
So what is the dimension of the
subspace?
Yeah,
three, good.
OK,
so this subspace is a
three-dimensional subspace of
R4.
What that means is that if I
were able to draw out the
collection of all vectors that
live in the subspace,
it would be a three-dimensional
slice of R4,
whatever that means.
Again, I can't visualize that
because I can't visualize an R4
but we should hope that it's
some flat slice of R4 that is
three-dimensional,
OK?
So is every vector in R4 in S?
No.
Only the vectors that live on
this slice are in S.
There's infinitely many that are
on the slice.
There's even more that are not
on the slice,
OK?
So S here is a three-dimensional
subspace
of R4.
So if I asked as a separate
question,
not find a basis, but I just
asked,
are these vectors linearly
independent?
What would you say?
You'd say no.
If I asked,
are these vectors a basis for
R4?
What would you say?
No.
Why are these vectors not a
basis for R4?
Well, there's two reasons for
that.
One,
they don't span all of R4.
They all live on a
three-dimensional slice of it.
So they don't even make up
everything.
And even if they somehow did,
they're linearly dependent,
okay?
So if,
again, this is a different
question than what I asked.
What we originally were working
through is find a basis for
their span.
Or that is find a basis for the
subspace I wrote up top.
But then if I instead just look
at the vectors I wrote up top
and say,
hey, do these span all of R4?
No.
Are they linearly independent?
No, so they're not a basis for
R4.
Okay,
yeah.
So just to clarify,
the only reason that we know
that that subspace
lives on R3 is because
we took the basis and the
dimension is 3.
Sorry,
let's be precise here.
What you're asking is the only
reason we know its dimension is
3 is because we found a basis
for it.
Yes.
It spans a three-dimensional
subspace of R4.
Yes.
There's no way that I could just
look at this and know instantly
that its dimension is 3.
I would need to work through
this process
and see that every basis I end
up with has three vectors in.
So if a question asks,
find the dimension of S,
what you would do is you would
work through this process and
see that the answer is 3.
Notice this is why I've
deliberately not said that a
vector with three components
has a dimension of 3,
because dimension is a property
that is of a subspace,
not of anything else.
So this subspace is a
three-dimensional subspace of
R4.
Awesome.
I have office hours after this,
like usual.
Otherwise, I might see you
tomorrow at the practice exam.
So like, you can't make this
using these two,
you can't make this using these
two, you
If all I'm asking you is to find
one basis, then yeah, but I can
make lots of bases that don't
involve mentors that were here,
like for example, like for
example,
just multiply this by two,
this by seven, and this by nine,
that's a new basis that didn't
involve How many of these
vectors are correct?
The number of vectors that are
linearly independent,
if it's correct, is the same as
the number of vectors that are
linearly independent.
A decision may or may not.
So like,
for example, if I,
and that's actually a homework
question.
If I have vectors that are
linearly independent,
are these linear combinations of
them also linearly independent?
The answer is that it kind of
depends.
Yeah.
I don't know if they're linearly
independent,
but like,
when they're linearly
independent, of course they're
not linearly independent.
That is exactly true.
And so like, we have a couple of
subs on the thing.
And so,
the thing that's complicated.
Or like subsets.
Sure.
So if you have,
like.
I was apparently surprised.
Subset,
a vector with a subset has an n
in it.
Or a sub,
and like, or a sub.
That's the way I usually think
of things.
So like, this is a vector with a
subset.
Well,
it might be if you look there.
I like,
I'm glad she's okay.
Here's the way to think about
why that's true.
If it were the case that you
could draw the function
anywhere, then any vector would
be on any curve.
If I could move the vector to
wherever I want it to be,
then this vector is on every
curve you could think If I'm
allowed to move,
you could draw any curve you
want.
I could move this vector so that
it points at 5, pardon me.
I don't think of the vectors as
starting at the origin.
Okay, so I should just think of
the vectors as starting at the
origin and then touch the line?
I was just saying a subset is
any collection of things,
a subspace is a special
collection where linear
combinations stay within the
subsets.
It's sort of motivation for what
is a subset that isn't a
subspace.
Because I want you to think
every subset is a subset.
Are there going to be questions
about like, is this in the
subset?
Or is that nothing but a thing?
I probably wouldn't have a
question that's like, here's a
random function, is this the
subspace or not? But like,
things like, you should be
familiar with that.
Thank you.
Anyways,
let's head outside so they can
dance at the police cars.
How do you feel about the
scissors?
I really didn't use partial
derivatives.
I forgot about that stuff.
The first unit,
I think was the hardest.
This stuff's not too bad.
I don't think this one was too
bad.